MÁRCIO FILIPE VILELA FONTES

birth 3/1994 e mfvfontes@gmail.com t 914696632 web marciofontes.pt



Student (5yrs) at FEUP, BSc owner (average 15.0), pationate for technology and focused in high-quality, adaptable, and intelligent software solutions. His academic experience encompasses projects for academic potential use. Beyond his passion for delivering great products and develop new ideas, he also focuses on writing, having already published on poetry anthologies.

Early 2015 he co-founded U.Project, a non-profit organization headquartered in UPTEC { http://www.uptec.up.pt}, which connects university students to promising startups. He has also assisted full-time professors on practical classes and giving support on projects related with Programming and Artificial Intelligence. On the last few months he has worked as a research fellow at Instituto de Telecomunicações.

Professional experience

DACT	EVDEDIENCE	IN ACADEMY
PASI	EAPERIENCE	IN ACADEMI

2016	Teaching Assistant - Artificial Intelligence, FEUP Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto { http:
	//www.fe.up.pt}
2016	Teaching Assistant - Programming, FEUP Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto { http://www.

2010	reaching Assistant - Hogramming, FEOF Tacutty of Engineering, University of Forto (neep.//www	
	fe.up.pt}	

2016	UP Show Staff Member, UP University of Porto { http://www.up.pt }
2016	FEUP Week Guide, FEUP Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto { http://www.fe.up.pt }
2010 — 12	Students Staff Member, COLGAIA Colégio de Gaia { http://www.colgaia.pt }

PAST EXPERIENCE IN INDUSTRY

2016 — 17	Research Fellow, Institute of Telecommunications, FEUP Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto {https:
	//www.it.pt/}

2015 - 16	Co-Founder and Vice-Presiden	t, U.Project { http://uproject.pt }
2011 - 12	Intern, Sublime Software, Lda.	<pre>{ http://sublimesoftware.pt }</pre>

Education

* 2012 — Integrated Msc in Informatics and Computing Engineering, FEUP, Average 15.0 out of 20 2009 — 12 Technician in Informatics and Multimedia Technologies, Colégio de Gaia, Average 19.1 out of 20

Grants, certifications, honors & awards

2015	Honorable Mention, Porto Graphics Game Jam, UniGlitch
2012	Best Technologic Project, Colégio de Gaia, Clavisom
2012	Best student of Informatics and Multimedia Technologies, Colégio de Gaia

Publications

воокѕ

2017 A Passagem. Chiado Editora.

PARTICIPATION IN BOOKS

A Passagem. Entre o Sono e o Sonho (Vol VII). Chiado Editora.

A Corrente. Entre o Sono e o Sonho (Vol IV). Chiado Editora.

Desassossego. Entre o Sono e o Sonho (Vol III). Chiado Editora.

CONFERENCE ARTICLES

António Lucas Soares, Márcio Fontes, "Learning for Practice Through Research Results in the Information Management Field", Proceedings of the iConference 2017, Wuhan, China.

Scientific services

CONFERENCE ORGANIZATION

2016 — 17 Conference Chair. TalkABit 5th Edition @ 2017, FEUP, Portugal.

EVENT ORGANIZATION

Staff Member. Lan Party @ 2012, COLGAIA, Portugal.

Staff Member. Expocolgaia @ 2012, COLGAIA, Portugal.

Staff Member. Lan Party @ 2011, COLGAIA, Portugal.

AFFILIATIONS

2014 — 16 Member. University of Porto IEEE Student Branch.

Main Projects

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

* 2016 — MUSICCHAT: A COLLABORATIVE SONG SHARING PLATFORM

Team Leader. Connect potential music talents with label companies, through a collaborative song sharing platform. Technologies: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, PHP

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

2016 TEXRESUME: RESUME GENERATOR WITH USER-DEFINED FIELDS

Team Leader. Enable users to write and customize their CV from many templates without internet connection, by creating new fields using AOM. Technologies: Adaptive Object Modeling, JAVA, TEXML, XML

2016 MANAGEMENT PLATFORM FOR THE VOLUNTEERING COMMISSION OF UNIVERSITY OF PORTO

Team Leader. Management platform using gamification strategies, based on Open Source solutions, which implements algorithms of optimization and allocation of resources. Technologies: BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, PHP, LARAVEL

2016 ELECTRONIC COMMERCE WITH BENEVOLENT CLIENTS

Developer. Implementation of electronic commerce scenarios which apply computational trust algorithms (Sinalpha trust model with and without benevolence). Technologies: JADE, JAVA

2016 FORECAST OF NEWS POPULARITY USING NEURAL NETWORKS

Developer. multi-layer neural network, implemented in Java using Back Propagation algorithm.	Tech-
nologies: Jblas, Weka, JAVA	

2016 CITYFIX - THE WORLD YOU KNOW. QUITE BETTER.

Scrum Master. Responsive website, meant for helping public entities to fix environmental issues more accurately, developed for Coding for Social Impact at FEUP. Technologies: BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, ANGULAR JS

2016 ENTERPRISE GENERIC DASHBOARD

Developer. Enterprise management website, using Primavera ERP. Technologies: Primavera ERP, C#, HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, PHP.

JJQUERY - JQUERY TO JAVA COMPILER

Developer. Compiler to perform collection selection operations using a jQuery-like syntax, embedded in Java code and to generate Java code from it. Technologies: JAVA, ANTLR

2015 F1 IN SCHOOLS

Developer. Management website for an international competition in which secondary school students employ CAD / CAM software to design miniature cars built in balsa wood and powered air. Technologies: BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, PHP, SMARTY

Main Developed Skills	COLÉGIO DE GAIA			FEUP				
Train 2 0 (orop our orang	09-10	10-11	11-12	12-13	13-14	14-15	15-16	16-17
FACULTY OF ENGINEERING OF UNIVERSITY OF	PORTO ·	COLÉGI	O DE GA	IA · 7 Y	EARS			
Databases		•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Web Development	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Computational Theory				•	•	•	•	•
Data Structures and Algorithms				•	•	•	•	•
Software Engineering						•	•	•
Logic Programming						•	•	•
Artificial Intelligence						•	•	•
Main Technical Skills	COL	ÉGIO DE O	GAIA			FEUP		
Main Technical Skins	09-10	10-11	11-12	12-13	13-14	14-15	15-16	16-17
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES								
Assembly				•	•	•	•	•
С	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
C++	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Java	•				•	•	•	•
Javascript	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
PhP	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Prolog	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•